JULIE ABRAHAM

1304 Blackburn Drive
Oakville, Ontario, L6M 2N5
(647) 302-4345

<u>Jabraham13@mac.com</u>
https://ca.linkedin.com/in/jabraham13

SUMMARY

- Medical image analysis, data mining, machine learning, web development.
- Extensive experience with C++, HTML5, Java, JavaScript, Python, R.

I am familiar with developing across multiple platforms and have experience providing documentation and support for users with a wide range of technical expertise.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER COMPUTATIONAL PATHOLOGY, PROTEOCYTE AI (2017 – 2018)

- Image analysis of whole slide images using Python with OpenCV libraries.
- Statistical analysis, survival models and machine learning with Python and R.
- Quality management for software systems (IEC 62304)
- Software source control using git with Atlassian Bitbucket.

Proteocyte AI develops a Machine Learning based test to determine a patient's risk for oral cancer based on a high resolution scan of a tissue sample. I worked on developing the model for the next version of the software.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, DENSITAS INC. (2015 – 2017)

- Image analysis of DICOM images in C++ using DCMTK and OpenCV libraries.
- Prototyping web apps with HTML5 and JavaScript.
- Creation of analysis and reporting tools in R.

Densitas Inc. creates medical device software. My role was to research new approaches to developing data driven software to complement existing products.

CONTRACTOR, DENSITAS INC. (2014)

• Created a plugin in Java for ImageJ image analysis software.

INFORMATION SYSTEMS TEAM, GLOBAL GRAPHICS (HARLEQUIN LTD), UK (1999 - 2000)

- Implemented rollout of Lotus Notes Domino server upgrade.
- Trained team members in using Lotus Notes Domino R5.
- Created custom web applications for internal company use.
- Ensured compatibility between Domino and Apache web servers.

DISCOVERY UNIT AND TEAMSPACE TEAM, ASPECTIVE (IVES & Co.), UK (1998 –1999)

- Prototyped new products for possible future development by the company.
- Developed new applications and upgraded existing ones using Lotus Notes Domino.

• Ensured consistent function of products in Notes client and in web browser using JavaScript and Java applets.

INFORMATION SYSTEMS TEAM, GLOBAL GRAPHICS (HARLEQUIN LTD), UK (1997 –1998)

- Developed and maintained data integration systems within the company.
- Extended existing Netscape website to include new Lotus Notes Domino web server.
- Built online payment application and integrated order information with sales and marketing systems.

ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT, IONICA PLC, (1996 –1997)

- Modeled telecommunications network traffic to facilitate load balancing across the network and maintain access for emergency services.
- Communicated with all other departments to determine the best way to acquire traffic data without compromising system security or functionality.
- Built a front end in MS Excel for traffic reporting which automatically queried data stored in an Oracle database.
- Documented all monitoring tools and interfaces for use by non-technical support staff.
- C, Oracle, Perl, Visual Basic.

VOLUNTEER WORK

ST BERNADETTE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, OAKVILLE (2008 – PRESENT)

- Help with elementary school science program, working with students in small groups to carry out a variety of experiments.
- Provide regular supplemental support to students with reading difficulties.
- Coordinate school events including budget and volunteer schedules.
- Design template documents in Microsoft Word and Adobe Illustrator for the teachers to use in their projects.

EDUCATION

Oxford University, 1995, Doctorate in Astrophysics

Imperial College, University of London, 1985, BSc (Hons) Physics